(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(APPLAUSE)
PADDY: Thank you.
Thank you, thank you,
thank you so much.
Hello and welcome to Top Gear.
And tonight it's the show
where Freddie nearly kills
all three of us.
Paddy, it was a little crash.
And, besides, it was your daft
idea in the first place.
-Lurch does make
a valid point here.
-Lurch?
-Lurch does make
a valid point here.
-Lurch?
-Lurch does make
a valid point here.
-Lurch?
He does, okay?
You've only got
yourself to blame.
He does, okay?
You've only got
yourself to blame.
It wasn't a daft idea.
It was a genius idea.
I reckoned I could
find the ultimate second-hand
family car on the cheap
I reckoned I could
find the ultimate second-hand
family car on the cheap
I reckoned I could
find the ultimate second-hand
family car on the cheap
I reckoned I could
find the ultimate second-hand
family car on the cheap
and then I went out
and bought myself one.
Families of Great Britain,
you can thank me later.
Makes you feel alive
driving a car like this.
Fred will love it for
the space and Chris
just for the drive quality.
Fred will love it for
the space and Chris
just for the drive quality.
Fred will love it for
the space and Chris
just for the drive quality.
FREDDIE: Whatever it is,
it better be good.
Oh. My. God.
-(HORN TOOTS)
-PADDY: Hey!
-CHRIS: What are you doing?
-FREDDIE: What's wrong with you?
What are you doing?
-What are you doing?
-The ultimate family car,
my friends.
-What are you doing?
-The ultimate family car,
my friends.
-What are you doing?
-The ultimate family car,
my friends.
1,300 quid for a Daimler,
posh and cheap,
a bit like you two.
1,300 quid for a Daimler,
posh and cheap,
a bit like you two.
1,300 quid for a Daimler,
posh and cheap,
a bit like you two.
1,300 quid for a Daimler,
posh and cheap,
a bit like you two.
-"Family"?
-PADDY: Yeah!
What, Addams Family?
-(CHRIS LAUGHING)
-1,300 quid for a Daimler, lads.
-FREDDIE: And your idea is
that this is family transport?
-PADDY: Absolutely.
-FREDDIE: And your idea is
that this is family transport?
-PADDY: Absolutely.
-FREDDIE: A hearse?
-Yeah.
So, you'd put your kids
in the back of that?
-Look at the room.
-FREDDIE: It's not
a case of room.
-Look at the room.
-FREDDIE: It's not
a case of room.
Of course it is. That's what all
family cars are about.
Space, getting things
in the back,
in and out easy,
Space, getting things
in the back,
in and out easy,
comfortable to drive, beautif.
-Death!
-FREDDIE: Yeah.
I've got something for you.
-Oh, there she is.
-PADDY: Have a look
under there, Christopher.
-Oh, there she is.
-PADDY: Have a look
under there, Christopher.
-(CHRIS WHISTLES)
-PADDY: Hey! Now,
look at his little face!
-(CHRIS WHISTLES)
-PADDY: Hey! Now,
look at his little face!
Is that a 3.2 or a 4 litre?
-PADDY: Four litre.
-CHRIS: Is it?
-PADDY: Straight six.
-The big donkey.
Look at him.
Look, he's changing already.
Chris, Chris, Chris, Chris, can
I stop you? Don't humour him.
-Look at you,
he's getting into it.
-I knew he'd like that.
-Look at you,
he's getting into it.
-I knew he'd like that.
Here, Fred.
Have a look at that.
Eh?
Yeah?
Shopping. Get yourself in here.
What are you, seven foot?
-Look at that, easy.
Look at that!
-Where's he gone?
-Look at that, easy.
Look at that!
-Where's he gone?
Where's he gone?
He's in there.
Look at the storage.
Where's he gone?
He's in there.
Look at the storage.
Why are you in there?
That's where dead people go!
PADDY: Look at that.
How's that for you?
FREDDIE: Yeah, room
for all the cricket
bags in for the kids.
FREDDIE: Yeah, room
for all the cricket
bags in for the kids.
Are you claustropho?
It doesn't matter.
Don't worry about it,
Are you claustropho?
It doesn't matter.
Don't worry about it,
-he's all right. In fact,
listen to that now.
-(BANGING)
-he's all right. In fact,
listen to that now.
-(BANGING)
-he's all right. In fact,
listen to that now.
-(BANGING)
-Oh, he's freaking out.
-You're coming out.
He's freaking out.
-PADDY: Are you all right, son?
-FREDDIE: It stinks in here,
by the way.
-PADDY: Are you all right, son?
-FREDDIE: It stinks in here,
by the way.
It stinks!
Yeah, let's get him out.
Here you are. Now, look at th.
Don't forget me,
Chris, I can't...
I don't want to end up
in the back
for real, do I? Eh?
I don't want to end up
in the back
for real, do I? Eh?
I don't want to end up
in the back
for real, do I? Eh?
Bloody hell!
Get in, I'll take you out for
a drive. I'll change your mind.
It just smells of death.
Forget that.
I'll get a magic tree from
a petrol station or something.
PADDY: Prepare to be impressed.
It's wet down here, Paddy.
Why is it wet down there?
PADDY: You don't want
to know what that is.
-FREDDIE: Tears.
-PADDY: Tears!
PADDY: Here we go, boys.
Straight six engine,
silky smooth,
240bhp.
I can see some of the appeal
of the six-cylinder engine.
I like the Daimler name.
Also, I love the XJ40 dashboa.
I mean, that was space age.
This is the classic Jaguar
J-Gate from the mid '90s,
so, what you do, these
are your normal driving modes
and you go across
to the sport mode.
-Now you can select
gears manually.
-PADDY: Lovely.
-Now you can select
gears manually.
-PADDY: Lovely.
-Now you can select
gears manually.
-PADDY: Lovely.
But how many miles has she do?
140,000.
-That's a lot.
-It is a lot in a normal car.
-Yeah.
-But that's 140,000 death miles.
-Death miles?
-And that's meant to sell it?
That's meant to sell it to me?
Death miles?
The most gentlest, lovely,
respectful miles you can have.
-This car's never been pushed.
-Paddy, what are
those down there?
-This car's never been pushed.
-Paddy, what are
those down there?
They don't look normal.
Now, I'm so glad
you've asked that.
You've gone to
the supermarket, right?
You've got your Viennettas
and your lollies in the back.
You get home to the kids,
they're excited,
it's all melted.
You get home to the kids,
they're excited,
it's all melted.
You get home to the kids,
they're excited,
it's all melted.
This, in the back,
pull them out...
cooling system in the back,
air con.
Keeps everything cold.
Why is there a cooling...
Oh, my...
PADDY: Clearly, the hearse
was something special.
I wouldn't want to be
seen dead in this car.
PADDY: And to find out
just how special,
we've been told
to head to the track
for a chance to show
what the ultimate family car
could really do.
Eurgh! There's a comb!
Yeah, that's mine.
That's why it's falling out.
That's why.
That's mine.
Have you seen
the mung on that?
Look at that.
Oh, no, that isn't mine.
That isn't...
No! Get off! Oh, no!
-Eyes on the road!
-No!
PADDY: As I was saying,
we'd been told to head to
the track for the chance
PADDY: As I was saying,
we'd been told to head to
the track for the chance
PADDY: As I was saying,
we'd been told to head to
the track for the chance
to show what the ultimate
family car can really do.
That...
is just a lot of vanilla.
CHRIS: Eyes right, boys.
Eyes right.
All right?
"Time to test your hearse
against some actual family cars.
"These, according to What Car?
magazine, are the finest
"on the market today."
That's a joke in itself.
"You will now take them on
in the Last Space Race."
FREDDIE: Oh, yes.
Recreating a battle played
out a thousand times a day
in every supermarket car park
across the land...
this would be a drag race
to the last three
parking spaces.
this would be a drag race
to the last three
parking spaces.
this would be a drag race
to the last three
parking spaces.
But first...
me and Harris had to choose
our own family car
to take on the hearse.
Now, I've decided
that I'm going to go for
the one that looks slow
Now, I've decided
that I'm going to go for
the one that looks slow
but is, in fact, I think, the
quickest, the VW Touran.
-FREDDIE: Whoa!
-Choose your own.
I'm going to beat you
in the Kia Sportage.
As long as one of us
beats the hearse.
Not one of us,
both of us, Chris.
Eh?
FREDDIE: Lads, I don't
want to put you off,
but in the car next to me
is Damon Hill.
Hey, Freddie, I think Damon's
won a Sports Personality
Of The Year as well.
It's not something
I like to bang on
about, Paddy, to be honest.
It's not something
I like to bang on
about, Paddy, to be honest.
It's not something
I like to bang on
about, Paddy, to be honest.
To be fair, Damon's
won it twice, though.
So, effectively, you're not even
the most popular sportsman
in a family-car drag race.
(ENGINES REVVING)
Have a bit of that, Damon.
Have a bit of that.
Flick it into sport mode.
Never mind Damon Hill.
Put him out of your mind.
It's all about the hearse.
Beat the hearse.
Drop that flag, sunshine.
Come on...
Ooh, straight off the line!
Fastest off the line.
It's nothing, this car.
It's nothing.
CHRIS: It's a good
start for Damon.
He's off.
CHRIS: It's a good
start for Damon.
He's off.
It's a good start,
but I've got him.
I've got him.
It's a good start,
but I've got him.
I've got him.
Oh, my God, look at the hearse.
Come on, Daimler!
I'm at the back.
No, come on, move!
CHRIS: Look at the hearse!
Look at the hearse!
Undertaker doing
a bit of overtaking.
Oh, not Paddy McGuinness.
Not in the hearse.
Right, three spaces.
I'm definitely second or third.
I'm going for that left spot.
Got to go for that left spot.
-You little swine!
-Yes.
Oh, my God, it's not stopping.
Oh, my God, it's not stopping!
Ooh.
(PADDY LAUGHS)
I have just beat Damon Hill...
in a drag race...
in a hearse.
Don't, don't, don't.
Oh, Little and Large,
glad you could make it.
Basically what's
happened while you
were pootling down there
Basically what's
happened while you
were pootling down there
-is we've just had a race.
-It's not whether you win,
it's how you win.
-is we've just had a race.
-It's not whether you win,
it's how you win.
How much is your motor?
What would you say? New.
Oh, 27,500, 33,000 as tested.
-£1,300.
-Yes.
It's just beat you.
It's a Daimler.
It's edging its way up to being
the ultimate family car, boys.
It's not!
Why is a family car
the car that is fastest
in a drag race?
Why is a family car
the car that is fastest
in a drag race?
Well... It's like building
a library in Bolton,
it's pointless.
Well... It's like building
a library in Bolton,
it's pointless.
Well... It's like building
a library in Bolton,
it's pointless.
I get it, lads. I get it.
You were nowhere near
and you're a little bit bitter,
you're a little bit angry.
Ey up.
You all right?
Oh, God, here we go.
"Because any good
family car must carry
a lot of stuff in its life,
"Because any good
family car must carry
a lot of stuff in its life,
"Because any good
family car must carry
a lot of stuff in its life,
-"next up is a
boot space challenge..."
-Oh, no!
-"next up is a
boot space challenge..."
-Oh, no!
"...where you will
pack your cars with as
many kilos of family stuff
"...where you will
pack your cars with as
many kilos of family stuff
"...where you will
pack your cars with as
many kilos of family stuff
-"as you can."
-Look at the size of it!
"Whoever has the most
is the winner."
If there's one car
that was built for
moving things, it was this!
If there's one car
that was built for
moving things, it was this!
If there's one car
that was built for
moving things, it was this!
Have you written
these challenges? Have you
written these challenges?
Have you written
these challenges? Have you
written these challenges?
It's just becoming
more and more...
Can we be clear about one thi?
It's not necessarily
how big your car is,
it's how you pack.
When you go away
on a family holiday,
it's how you pack.
When you go away
on a family holiday,
there's a strategy to packing
and I think you're a bit gung ho
and a bit overconfident.
I think some
clever packaging in these
very practical cars could
I think some
clever packaging in these
very practical cars could
-still win this.
-Yes, I actually think
he's onto something there.
-still win this.
-Yes, I actually think
he's onto something there.
Now, do you want
to swap your car?
You can swap your car.
I don't mind.
You can take Hill's Berlingo
for all I care.
Damon!
PADDY: So,
the challenge was simple.
Before us lay everything
you'd ever expect a good
family car to carry.
Before us lay everything
you'd ever expect a good
family car to carry.
Before us lay everything
you'd ever expect a good
family car to carry.
Before us lay everything
you'd ever expect a good
family car to carry.
Our job was to cram as much
of it in as we could...
(HOOTER BLOWS)
...in just ten minutes.
And I had, let's be honest,
nothing to worry about.
Look at the space!
Because while strategic Harris
was taking things seriously...
Neat and tidy
is the way forward.
PADDY: ...unfortunately,
he'd parked too close
to a man who wasn't.
PADDY: ...unfortunately,
he'd parked too close
to a man who wasn't.
PADDY: ...unfortunately,
he'd parked too close
to a man who wasn't.
Are you going for it, Harris?
-No, you can't...
-These look heavy.
You...
Yeah, that will do.
Just back up to the old ladies.
Go away!
Chris, Chris, Chris...
There's your keys.
Ladies, I'm a bit
of a gentleman,
so I'd never ask anybody
Ladies, I'm a bit
of a gentleman,
so I'd never ask anybody
Ladies, I'm a bit
of a gentleman,
so I'd never ask anybody
how old they are,
but who's heaviest?
No, you can't ask that.
-Oh!
-I'm just giving these ladies...
Paddy, you can't...
Giving these ladies a hug.
Yeah, come on,
come with me, madam.
There you go.
That's it.
Here you go, Pat.
Make yourself at home.
Have a potato, have a swede.
Over there,
that's Sir Freddie Flintoff.
No, I need weight.
As you can see...
No.
...he's not very well-adjusted.
Let him get out the way.
He's not safe.
Right, I'm not sure
I can do much more.
CHRIS: With just a minute
left on the clock,
and all three cars
CHRIS: With just a minute
left on the clock,
and all three cars
CHRIS: With just a minute
left on the clock,
and all three cars
almost full, it looked
like my strategy might
just be paying off.
almost full, it looked
like my strategy might
just be paying off.
almost full, it looked
like my strategy might
just be paying off.
Until, all of a sudden...
-Paddy, Paddy.
-CHRIS: ...it wasn't.
Let's empty it.
No, no!
Go on, Paddy! Go on, Paddy!
Go on, Paddy!
Let's put this in the car.
Hey, I've got something.
It was funny this morning,
wasn't it, with my head?
Put him in, bit of ballast.
(BLEEP)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Don't worry if you hear
anybody in the back, madam.
It's just Chris Harris.
(HOOTER BLOWS)
CHRIS: Where did they find you?
You're an animal.
Everything all right, boys?
All right, Pad?
(LAUGHTER)
Perfect shape for his head.
Just perfect. Like, bang.
Full teapot here. Full teapot!
I'm not bothered.
You are feral.
If you were a cat,
they'd spay you.
You should not
be allowed to reproduce.
You're all kinds of wrong.
You should not
be allowed to reproduce.
You're all kinds of wrong.
You should not
be allowed to reproduce.
You're all kinds of wrong.
You've picked me up,
rag-dolled me round,
you've thrown me
into a coffin hole
and locked me there and,
you've thrown me
into a coffin hole
and locked me there and,
answer me this,
how did you manage
to cut my head with a melon?
answer me this,
how did you manage
to cut my head with a melon?
answer me this,
how did you manage
to cut my head with a melon?
Never mind that,
you find it funny when I get
a heavy wooden latch on my he.
I attack you with
a soft fruit and, look at him,
he's whingeing, isn't he?
I attack you with
a soft fruit and, look at him,
he's whingeing, isn't he?
Using Chris as a juicer aside,
it still... it is
a perfect shape, isn't it?
You can really get
a good squeeze on that.
It's still 2-0 to the hearse.
Right, won the
Last Space Race challenge,
won the loading-up challenge.
I've told you, UFC,
Ultimate Family Car.
Well, we'll see just how
ultimate later in the show.
-Oh, he's off again.
-But, first, a question.
Bugatti Veyron,
the gorgeous Alfa 8C,
and a Haas Formula 1 car.
Can anyone tell me which car
company connects all of these?
No, but I think
I know a man who is.
(LAUGHING SARCASTICALLY)
I'm going to tell you. Draw up
the comfy chair, Patrick.
(LAUGHING SARCASTICALLY)
I'm going to tell you. Draw up
the comfy chair, Patrick.
I will.
CHRIS: Allow me
to introduce Dallara...
the greatest car company
you've never heard of.
For half a century,
in a small corner of Italy,
its engineers have helped
to create some of the world's
greatest automotive hits.
But now...
Dallara has decided
to take centre stage.
This...
is the Stradale.
That's Italian for road.
Yes, this is a road car.
But, really, you want
to get it on a track.
Wow. Whoo!
What a little thing.
0-60 takes just over
three seconds.
Flat out, it will do 174mph.
But, in the Stradale,
it's how eager
it is to get there
But, in the Stradale,
it's how eager
it is to get there
But, in the Stradale,
it's how eager
it is to get there
that really gets
your blood pumping.
Put your foot down and it just
picks up straight away.
A little racing car
with a number plate.
God, the brakes are handy, too.
And that's because
the Stradale is light.
Really light.
Dallara has built
the Stradale almost
entirely of carbon fibre.
Dallara has built
the Stradale almost
entirely of carbon fibre.
Dallara has built
the Stradale almost
entirely of carbon fibre.
The skeleton and bodywork
are carbon fibre,
most of the interior,
even the cup-holder.
All in, this car
tips the scales
at a race-car-rivalling
900 kilos,
and the motorsport know-how
doesn't end there.
You know what separates
proper race cars from just
the regular fast stuff?
It's not power.
It's downforce.
This car is all about
the downforce.
Flat out, the Stradale
makes a mighty 800 kilos
of the stuff.
Flat out, the Stradale
makes a mighty 800 kilos
of the stuff.
Flat out, the Stradale
makes a mighty 800 kilos
of the stuff.
Those massive scoops
behind the wheels,
that enormous rear wing,
they're manipulating the airflow
over the car
to literally stick it
to the surface of the track.
over the car
to literally stick it
to the surface of the track.
over the car
to literally stick it
to the surface of the track.
over the car
to literally stick it
to the surface of the track.
And that means
it can do this.
A-ha!
That's proper grip!
You can literally feel
the weight of the air
pushing the car down.
It's like a paper dart.
This thing is so sharp.
Dallara says this will produce
lateral forces of 2Gs.
It's race car G-force.
It's the kind of G-force that
makes you feel like your brain's
about to leak out of your ears.
Oh, yes!
Woohoo.
Impressive stuff,
but, the Stradale does
have a couple of problems.
Impressive stuff,
but, the Stradale does
have a couple of problems.
Impressive stuff,
but, the Stradale does
have a couple of problems.
Impressive stuff,
but, the Stradale does
have a couple of problems.
Firstly...
they don't seem to have
quite finished the doors.
Give me a second.
Right.
If I'm being honest,
it's not the most
elegant supercar
If I'm being honest,
it's not the most
elegant supercar
If I'm being honest,
it's not the most
elegant supercar
to look at.
And, whilst the interior's
very well made, there's...
not much of it.
And, whilst the interior's
very well made, there's...
not much of it.
And, whilst the interior's
very well made, there's...
not much of it.
Put it this way,
if you want sat nav and music,
you'd better make
sure that your passenger
can read a map and sing.
you'd better make
sure that your passenger
can read a map and sing.
you'd better make
sure that your passenger
can read a map and sing.
Plus, this Stradale
will set you back £200,000,
which is... a lot.
Especially for a car that isn't
fitted with a V12 or a V10
or a V8 or even a V6.
No, it's powered
by a four-cylinder
engine from a Ford.
No, it's powered
by a four-cylinder
engine from a Ford.
No, it's powered
by a four-cylinder
engine from a Ford.
No, it's powered
by a four-cylinder
engine from a Ford.
But...
in a machine where
every gram counts,
a four-cylinder
Ford engine...
is exactly what
this car needs.
That little 2.3 litre
turbo-four,
that provides maximum power
for minimum weight.
400 horsepower
is plenty to get on
with when you've got 900kg.
This is the antidote
to all those big, pudgy,
fat, overweight hyper-cars.
Dallara's doing it right.
This is a supercar
for the chassis enthusiast.
I know that sounds a bit niche,
a bit like having a thing
for elbows, but if you care
more about how a car drives
than how it sounds,
if you care more
about steering feel
than how it sounds,
if you care more
about steering feel
than how it sounds,
if you care more
about steering feel
than Instagram likes,
then this could well be
the supercar for you.
Whoo!
Look at that!
My name is Chris Harris
and I am a chassis enthusiast.
CHRIS:
That is a fantastic little car.
Delicate, fast.
Now, I know, Chris,
you're a massive
chassis enthusiast
Now, I know, Chris,
you're a massive
chassis enthusiast
Now, I know, Chris,
you're a massive
chassis enthusiast
and I'm sure this
car is amazing to drive,
but it's 200 grand.
-It's got a Ford engine.
-Yeah.
It's got a name no-one's
heard of and as much
power as a hot hatch.
It's got a name no-one's
heard of and as much
power as a hot hatch.
I'm with Fred on this one.
If you're spending 200 grand
on a car,
I'm with Fred on this one.
If you're spending 200 grand
on a car,
I'm with Fred on this one.
If you're spending 200 grand
on a car,
you want people
to stop and stare.
You don't want them to stop
and Google what the hell it is.
This is a car
for someone that wants
to be connected
to the driving experience,
not a peacock from Cheshire.
It's a great car. It's gorgeo.
-But how quick is it
around the track?
-Very.
-But how quick is it
around the track?
-Very.
-But how quick is it
around the track?
-Very.
The Stig took it out earlier
today and you can
see the lap online,
The Stig took it out earlier
today and you can
see the lap online,
but how fast do you think it ?
How far up this board
are we going, Chris?
It's going beyond my reach.
-I think it's up here.
-Well, that's not
that far, is it?
-I think it's up here.
-Well, that's not
that far, is it?
Right up there.
I walked
straight into that, didn't I?
-I've got the results,
and I can tell you...
-Yeah.
-I've got the results,
and I can tell you...
-Yeah.
-...the Dallara Stradale...
-Stradale?
...Stradale went round our
track in one minute...
Yeah, get it out.
-...12...
-Ooh!
-...point eight!
-Whoa!
-The second-fastest
round the track.
-Wow!
-The second-fastest
round the track.
-Wow!
Does that surprise you?
Yeah, I didn't think
it would be that quick. Amazing.
-Unbelievable.
-Well done, little car.
That is very quick, very quick.
Right, time to meet our
celebrity guests who tonight
are sporting royalty,
Zara and Mike Tindall.
Here's what happened
when they arrived at our
track earlier today.
Here's what happened
when they arrived at our
track earlier today.
Look who's here.
-Hi, guys.
-Hello, how are you.
-ZARA: I'm good.
-Good to see you.
What we have here
is the width restrictor
challenge, okay, guys?
What we have here
is the width restrictor
challenge, okay, guys?
What we have here
is the width restrictor
challenge, okay, guys?
So, we've got two sturdy
width restrictors here
and they're about
So, we've got two sturdy
width restrictors here
and they're about
So, we've got two sturdy
width restrictors here
and they're about
seven feet apart, which gives
you about an inch either side
of the wing mirrors
to get through.
The winner is the one that goes
through there quickest
as according to that speed gun.
You each have to choose
a partner in crime,
or ballast or whichever
way you look at it.
I'm going to choose
the... racing driver.
-Yes!
-Him?
That's a mistake.
I've chosen to go
with who I think
is probably the most reckless.
I've chosen to go
with who I think
is probably the most reckless.
I've chosen to go
with who I think
is probably the most reckless.
-Bit awkward, Paddy.
-Right, okay, let's go.
Get a crash helmet.
CHRIS: Okay,
here's the strategy.
You can't lift. You have
to just go flat out
the whole way there.
You can't lift. You have
to just go flat out
the whole way there.
You can't lift. You have
to just go flat out
the whole way there.
Why are you fixing
the rear view mirror?
I don't know.
Are you ready, Chris?
CHRIS: Yeah, we're ready.
Just bury your foot.
-There she goes.
-Oh, it's a bit slow.
This is a real Jaguar, an XJ .
Listen to that V8 purring.
Here they come. They're coming.
CHRIS: Come to me a little bit.
Come to me a little bit.
Right, here we go. Here we go!
And suddenly it's coming
at us quite quickly.
-PADDY: Oh, oh, oh, oh!
-CHRIS: Keep going, keep going!
-Oh, no!
-And she nearly got the camera!
-It's not broken.
-ZARA: No.
-FREDDIE: Wow.
-PADDY: Oh, dear.
Look at her.
Smug, that, isn't it?
Whoa! Hey!
Yes!
FREDDIE: Can we just check
the wing mirror, please?
PADDY: Oh, it's still on.
There is nothing wrong
with that wing mirror.
PADDY: It still on,
it's all right, Chris.
-Zara, that was fast.
That was fast.
-ZARA: How fast was it?
-Zara, that was fast.
That was fast.
-ZARA: How fast was it?
-Zara, that was fast.
That was fast.
-ZARA: How fast was it?
-I stopped looking after 90.
-She was buried the whole way.
-Didn't lift at all.
-Really?
-Didn't lift.
-Chris is excited.
-Ninety-eight.
-Wow!
-That's fast.
-That's pretty fast,
that's pretty fast.
-That's fast.
-That's pretty fast,
that's pretty fast.
-That's fast.
-That's pretty fast,
that's pretty fast.
I tell you something as well,
I think you're in with a chance
-because look at the size
of these two.
-I know.
-because look at the size
of these two.
-I know.
There's an instant half
a tonne added on to the car.
Right, in you get, boys.
Best of luck to you.
We're going.
-What's the tactic, then?
Just don't lift off?
-Yeah.
-What's the tactic, then?
Just don't lift off?
-Yeah.
-What's the tactic, then?
Just don't lift off?
-Yeah.
-ZARA: I hope he smashes it.
-CHRIS: Here they come.
Here we go.
Now coming up to 80.
Don't lift off. 90.
Here we go.
Now coming up to 80.
Don't lift off. 90.
Oh, my God. That's fast.
Go, go, go, go, go!
Go on, Mike!
Oh!
(LAUGHTER)
That is definitely...
That is definitely discounted.
-Yes!
-It's a reasonable shunt, that.
Well, do you want the good
news or the bad news?
There is no bad news, Paddy.
It's all good.
-I'll give you
the good news first.
-It was fast?
-I'll give you
the good news first.
-It was fast?
-I'll give you
the good news first.
-It was fast?
Hundred-and-seven.
Very, very, very fast.
Bad news, doesn't count.
You're disqualified because
you broke the wing mirror.
-Anyhow, you've won that.
-Yes.
It's all about the lap now.
It's all about the lap.
Ladies and gentlemen,
fresh from causing carnage
on the track,
Zara and Mike Tindall.
-Hello.
Was it fun? Was it fun?
Sit yourselves down.
Wowzers.
Mike, you took
a chunk out of the
bollard there, my friend.
Mike, you took
a chunk out of the
bollard there, my friend.
Mike, you took
a chunk out of the
bollard there, my friend.
Well, we were generally
having a chat about what would
happen if we
just smashed straight
through it, me and Fred,
happen if we
just smashed straight
through it, me and Fred,
and I think it was
still in my head
about whether I could turn
and I think it was
still in my head
about whether I could turn
and I think it was
still in my head
about whether I could turn
into it just before.
Cos I know you've got
a bit of a history.
I mean, you crashed a car
at the age of five.
You were supposed to crash
them, they were dodgems.
Oh, you were in a dodgem.
Is that when you
first broke your nose?
Oh, you were in a dodgem.
Is that when you
first broke your nose?
-Without your seat belt on.
-How many times have
you broke your nose?
-Without your seat belt on.
-How many times have
you broke your nose?
-Without your seat belt on.
-How many times have
you broke your nose?
-Eight.
-Eight times?
I assume they broke
it when they straightened
it as well, so nine.
I assume they broke
it when they straightened
it as well, so nine.
It did end up looking like that
bollard that you hit before.
-It was very similar.
-Pretty much, it was.
The old nose,
I could have probably
nestled it in and got a nice
The old nose,
I could have probably
nestled it in and got a nice
The old nose,
I could have probably
nestled it in and got a nice
shape to it.
Pulled the shape back out.
Any other sporting injuries
from your career?
I have, yeah, a few.
Uh, best sounding
one is when I landed
on the back of Lee Byrne's heel
Uh, best sounding
one is when I landed
on the back of Lee Byrne's heel
Uh, best sounding
one is when I landed
on the back of Lee Byrne's heel
Uh, best sounding
one is when I landed
on the back of Lee Byrne's heel
and broke two of my ribs,
punctured my lung
and lacerated my liver.
and broke two of my ribs,
punctured my lung
and lacerated my liver.
-Ooh!
-You lacerated your liver?
Yeah. I was
in intensive care
for five days.
Yeah. I was
in intensive care
for five days.
Have you ever picked
up any injuries
like that in cricket, Fred?
Have you ever picked
up any injuries
like that in cricket, Fred?
Like cutting yourself
on a cucumber sandwich or...
I've over-eaten a few times.
But, Zara, you drive
stuff bigger now.
You've got an HGV licence.
But, Zara, you drive
stuff bigger now.
You've got an HGV licence.
But, Zara, you drive
stuff bigger now.
You've got an HGV licence.
I do. I can drive my truck.
Cos we all drive our horses
around, we drive them
to competitions,
so we need a big
vehicle to obviously get them
to competitions,
so we need a big
vehicle to obviously get them
to competitions,
so we need a big
vehicle to obviously get them
to the competitions
and all their kit
and all our kit,
to the competitions
and all their kit
and all our kit,
to the competitions
and all their kit
and all our kit,
so, yeah, I love it.
(IMPERSONATES HORN)
-Yeah!
-I've got one question
about transporting horses.
-Yeah!
-I've got one question
about transporting horses.
-Yeah!
-I've got one question
about transporting horses.
It's a big animal,
they need to hydrate,
but if they have
a big wee when
you're on the road,
but if they have
a big wee when
you're on the road,
-where does the wee go?
-They stop at the services.
What do you think?
-where does the wee go?
-They stop at the services.
What do you think?
-where does the wee go?
-They stop at the services.
What do you think?
-Are you competitive
in the car, you two?
-No.
-Are you competitive
in the car, you two?
-No.
Who wants to be driving?
If we go out together,
I'll generally drive, won't I?
Oh, here we go!
-Yeah.
-Just cos she likes a drink.
ZARA: Oh, my God...
Generally, I would drive,
but, yeah, it's not...
Normally because I'm putting
food in the back seat,
-trying to keep a child quiet.
-Babies.
Who's got the bragging rights
over the stereo?
What do you listen to?
-He loves a musical.
-Oh, no!
FREDDIE: Get in!
What's your favourite, Mike?
Sit back, lads. We've got this.
What's your favourite?
See, Rock Of Ages,
I do enjoy.
Obviously, A Star Is Born
is big at the moment.
Anyway, the lap.
Mike, you've won
a Rugby World Cup.
Anyway, the lap.
Mike, you've won
a Rugby World Cup.
Anyway, the lap.
Mike, you've won
a Rugby World Cup.
Zara, you're an eventing
world champion.
But this is the big one.
This is the Top Gear track.
Well, it's 1-0 so far
cos you obviously won
-the width restrictor challenge.
-I'm happy I got on the board.
Zara, who do
the family want to win?
-Me.
-Oh, of course they do.
Hello!
And to add a little bit
of spice to the lap,
we decided that
you are going to go
in the cars together.
we decided that
you are going to go
in the cars together.
we decided that
you are going to go
in the cars together.
We're going to have
a look at Zara's lap first,
but, before we do,
we're just going
to have a look at
one of your practice laps.
we're just going
to have a look at
one of your practice laps.
Would you care
to talk us through what
happened here, Zara, please?
Would you care
to talk us through what
happened here, Zara, please?
No lifting! No lifting!
Oh!
That was your no lifting.
Well, that's a performance lap.
I do like the fact
that immediately
it was his fault
I do like the fact
that immediately
it was his fault
I do like the fact
that immediately
it was his fault
for telling you not to lift.
I love the fact
that you were just
having a nice conversation
I love the fact
that you were just
having a nice conversation
I love the fact
that you were just
having a nice conversation
as the car was spinning.
CHRIS: Yeah, utterly fearless.
Anyway, who would like
to see Zara's timed lap?
PADDY: Yes, come on.
FREDDIE: Let's have a look.
CHRIS: Off the line.
Good, solid start,
that, I think.
Good, solid start.
Good, solid start,
that, I think.
Good, solid start.
Yes!
CHRIS: A little bit slower
because you've got basically
about four bags of
potatoes next to you.
ZARA: Exactly! Thank you.
CHRIS: Slowing you down.
CHRIS: The line's good and
the car looks quick.
-Does it?
-CHRIS: It does.
Yes!
CHRIS: Gear change is right.
You've run a bit wide there,
a bit too wide.
Bring it back in.
You've run a bit wide there,
a bit too wide.
Bring it back in.
-Let's go! Come on!
-Change!
I've seen you drive
faster to Waitrose.
CHRIS: Braking now...
That's always a good sign,
when you trigger those hazard
CHRIS: Braking now...
That's always a good sign,
when you trigger those hazard
warning lights, that means
you're at the
maximum braking.
warning lights, that means
you're at the
maximum braking.
And also seeing the circuit,
cause it's so flat,
knowing where
And also seeing the circuit,
cause it's so flat,
knowing where
the corners are
is quite tricky as well.
You can't see them.
(ZARA CLICKING TONGUE)
CHRIS: Now, the Follow-through.
This is good.
And it's a damp surface.
This is where
I clench my buttocks.
PADDY: That's a thought!
Whoo!
Oh, lovely, though. Smooth.
I think this is quick, my love.
CHRIS: Second to last.
I don't think you can go
much quicker through there.
CHRIS: Second to last.
I don't think you can go
much quicker through there.
CHRIS: Second to last.
I don't think you can go
much quicker through there.
That's a fantastic line.
Using all the circuit.
Oh, oh, oh...
Argh!
CHRIS: This is good, look.
A bit of a bump. Bang.
PADDY: Yeah, gone.
Gone.
-FREDDIE:
I think you're nervous.
-I am!
-FREDDIE:
I think you're nervous.
-I am!
Are you nervous?
I just wanted to make
The Stig proud.
-FREDDIE: You wanted
to make The Stig proud?
-PADDY: You will.
-FREDDIE: You wanted
to make The Stig proud?
-PADDY: You will.
You can see the lap board.
Where do you think
you're going to be, Zara?
Who are you eyeing up on there?
I hope I've beaten
Frankie Dettori.
-That would make my day.
-CHRIS: For obvious reasons.
Zara, I can tell you,
you went round our track
in one minute...
It makes me nervous
when you've looked
down the board.
It makes me nervous
when you've looked
down the board.
-I'm looking at it...
-You could have gone...
Instead of starting at the top,
he started at the bottom.
I'm good at poker as well.
One minute, 40...
one...
-point six.
-Good effort.
ZARA: I think that's okay.
PADDY: Wow,
that's good. Up there.
That's good, Zara. That's good.
On a damp.
Well above Dettori.
You were on a damp.
That's a great time.
CHRIS: Dettori who?
Shall we have
a look at Mike's lap?
Yes, come on.
Let's have a look.
-Good luck.
-Thanks.
CHRIS: Right, off the line.
Come on, come on, come on!
CHRIS: Well, it's your own
weight slowing you
down this time,
so we can't really blame
anyone for that, can we?
You've run wide there,
bit too wide. Windscreen
wipers were put on
You've run wide there,
bit too wide. Windscreen
wipers were put on
for effect, it wasn't really
raining, was it?
That's a good line.
Direction change
into Chicago.
That's a good line.
Direction change
into Chicago.
Oh, I'm in fourth, (BLEEP)
CHRIS: He's triggered
those lights again.
That's good.
CHRIS: He's triggered
those lights again.
That's good.
CHRIS: He's triggered
those lights again.
That's good.
I feel like you're harder
on the brakes than I was.
CHRIS: I love the way
you've put the windscreen
wipers on
CHRIS: I love the way
you've put the windscreen
wipers on
to make us think
that you think
it's wet, but it's not.
to make us think
that you think
it's wet, but it's not.
-It was raining!
-It was bone dry.
CHRIS: That's sunshine.
There's sunshine on the car.
I've got this, baby.
I've got this.
CHRIS: Oh, a bit
of oversteer, showboating.
You lifted off. Lifted off!
-I didn't lift off.
-You did.
I wanted to get a lap in.
Ah!
CHRIS: He likes
to get the backend
moving around, doesn't he?
CHRIS: He likes
to get the backend
moving around, doesn't he?
That's really good
through there,
that's a very fast line.
That's really good
through there,
that's a very fast line.
That's really good
through there,
that's a very fast line.
Through Gambon.
Yeah, that looked quick.
PADDY: Got there in the end.
But I wouldn't want to call it.
What are you thinking, Mike?
Do you think you've beat her?
-That's too close to call,
too close to call.
-Do you think?
-That's too close to call,
too close to call.
-Do you think?
-Yes.
-If you're saying that...
If I'm somewhere around
there, I'd be happy.
Zara is 1-0 up already.
-They are both damp laps.
-She's hammered me.
Damp? It was sunny.
He's got a D as well,
but, Mike Tindall,
I can tell you, you went
round the track in one minute...
-40...
-(GASPS)
point five.
Oh, well done. Well done.
Oh!
Just above Jason Manford.
That's a good lap.
Very good lap.
And that's damp as well.
So, let's just say,
if you're weather-adjusted,
you're getting up
towards the Ross Nobles
of this world, I think.
you're getting up
towards the Ross Nobles
of this world, I think.
-I'm happy to give you that one.
-Thanks.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Zara and Mike Tindall.
Now, Paddy, earlier on,
you were trying to convince us
that 1,300 quid gets you
a Daimler hearse
-as the ultimate family car.
-Correct.
I'm going to tell you, though,
-I think you might be
on to something.
-Thank you.
-I think you might be
on to something.
-Thank you.
But Fred and I reckoned
it could be even more ultimate.
So, we took
the hearse off to make
a few minor upgrades,
So, we took
the hearse off to make
a few minor upgrades,
and a few days later,
met up with Paddy in Tenby.
Go on, Tenby.
I cannot wait to show Paddy
what we've done to this car.
(CAR HORN TOOTS)
(PADDY CHUCKLES)
Oh!
The boys, look
what they've done!
(CAR HONKS)
Let's show him...
-I can't wait.
-...this genius.
I knew it had potential,
but I didn't know
it had this much potential.
First of all, pop that bonnet.
Okay, that is
a 350 horsepower Lexus V8
straight out of an LS400.
(ENGINE REVS)
This is now the best sounding
car in the car park.
Paddy, just feast your eyes
down here. Look at this.
A splitter. It's just
the little things, it makes
such a difference.
A splitter. It's just
the little things, it makes
such a difference.
Little things count, don't th?
And the colour,
Volvo Polestar blue.
The great combination, Volvo,
safety, family safety,
Polestar, racing.
In a colour, blue.
I've got to tell you,
lads, I like it.
FREDDIE: And so he should
because this was
no longer a hearse.
FREDDIE: And so he should
because this was
no longer a hearse.
FREDDIE: And so he should
because this was
no longer a hearse.
This was The Overtaker.
And, to make it,
we also blagged
all-terrain tyres,
And, to make it,
we also blagged
all-terrain tyres,
And, to make it,
we also blagged
all-terrain tyres,
a massive rear spoiler,
quad exhausts,
a ball pool for when
the kids are good
and, for when they're not,
a naughty step.
1,300 quid!
Look at all that for 1,300 qu.
Do you think we've
taken your idea,
which we now agree was quite
clever, and we've run with it?
Absolutely.
-Hello.
-You all right?
"Your ultimate
family car will now
face the ultimate test,
"Your ultimate
family car will now
face the ultimate test,
"Your ultimate
family car will now
face the ultimate test,
-"a family holiday in Wales."
Love it.
-Oh!
-"a family holiday in Wales."
Love it.
-Oh!
"Along the way,
you will tackle the best
in the family car business.
"Along the way,
you will tackle the best
in the family car business.
"Along the way,
you will tackle the best
in the family car business.
"First, head down to the beach
for some bucket and spading."
Fingers crossed we do a bit
of crabbing as well.
Right, get in, lads.
I've got to say, I love
that starter button, boys.
-Do you want to press it?
-May I?
Yeah, of course.
Go on.
You're good to go. Go on.
(ENGINE REVVING)
FREDDIE: So began
the Overtaker's
maiden voyage
FREDDIE: So began
the Overtaker's
maiden voyage
and what might just be
the first family holiday ever
where everyone
was actually looking
forward to the drive.
where everyone
was actually looking
forward to the drive.
where everyone
was actually looking
forward to the drive.
The Etch A Sketch!
Oh, yes, nature's iPad.
FREDDIE:
Yep, we'd even packed stuff
to keep the kids quiet,
FREDDIE:
Yep, we'd even packed stuff
to keep the kids quiet,
FREDDIE:
Yep, we'd even packed stuff
to keep the kids quiet,
while the grown-ups talk.
I tell you what,
I can just feel it rumbling
underneath my right foot.
I tell you what,
I can just feel it rumbling
underneath my right foot.
I think most of the residents
of Tenby can as well!
Like an AMG.
FREDDIE: But, in an AMG,
you don't get one of these.
Oh!
Oh, boys!
It's like the school tuck shop.
Liquorice all sorts,
Haribos, Sports Mixture...
Double Deckers.
The one thing
I'm glad you've not put
in there is a Turkish Delight.
The one thing
I'm glad you've not put
in there is a Turkish Delight.
The one thing
I'm glad you've not put
in there is a Turkish Delight.
The devil's work.
That is basically
a chocolate-covered
toilet block.
That is basically
a chocolate-covered
toilet block.
That is basically
a chocolate-covered
toilet block.
It is horrendous.
CHRIS: Now, this
is very important.
I'm going to show you
our onboard Hoover.
Oh, thank God
that's what that is!
When you pulled that out
from in between your legs,
I thought, "What is he
using that for?"
FREDDIE: Soon, in some
typically British weather,
we arrived at our first
FREDDIE: Soon, in some
typically British weather,
we arrived at our first
FREDDIE: Soon, in some
typically British weather,
we arrived at our first
family holiday
stop-off, the beach.
PADDY: Here we go, boys.
This is the life.
Our first family
holiday in Wales.
Look at it!
FREDDIE: And lying in wait...
PADDY: Hang on,
hang on, hang on.
FREDDIE: ...was
our first rival.
PADDY: What the hell's that?
CHRIS:
That is an AMG E63 S Estate.
Oh!
-We can't see.
-Fred, follow him.
FREDDIE: That cheeky...
That was cheeky!
FREDDIE: Our first challenge
would be a fastest-lap battle
against the Merc on
a specially designed
course right on the sand.
against the Merc on
a specially designed
course right on the sand.
against the Merc on
a specially designed
course right on the sand.
Because, in the world
of family cars,
the E63 is
the daddy of them all.
And, if that wasn't enough,
this one was manned
by a family
of rival holiday-makers.
Okay, Stig, are you ready?
Take that as a yeah?
Think it's a yeah.
Three, two, one, go!
FREDDIE: 0-60 in 3.5 seconds.
He is using...
Look, he's going sideways.
You know what?
Over 100 grand, that car.
FREDDIE: For an estate car.
Not sure I'm having that.
PADDY: I'm not
sure I'm having that.
That thing's got twice
the power this thing's got.
Look at him, he's coming in n.
1:09.28.
Where's he going?
What... What's
he doing? He's gone.
PADDY: (OVER RADIO)
Harris, 1:09.
That's the time
you've got to beat.
Do not let us down.
-He's got no chance.
-I know.
Three, two, one, go.
She's a bit sluggish
off the line.
Slow and steady wins the race.
It's a thing of beauty. Look.
Where's he going?
He's getting it sideways
round that first one.
Yes, come on! The Overtaker!
I tell you what, to be fair,
he's done all right there.
There she goes.
-FREDDIE: Go on, Harris!
-PADDY: Go on, Harris!
Go on, sunshine!
PADDY: Now, this is where
it gets tricky now,
as he comes into the canoes.
Watch this.
Come on!
You can feel the victory.
Go on!
And over the line.
Lost a few balls.
That felt fast.
It wasn't bad, Harris.
(OVER RADIO) 1:14.69.
I think that's a great effort.
We got very close.
You were five seconds slower,
but if we equate that
to pounds and pence,
the Overtaker's
cost us 1,300 quid.
That E63 is over £100,000,
so I'm putting this down
as a moral victory for us.
PADDY: So, that's
1-0 to the Overtaker,
which meant we could get back
to enjoying our holiday.
You can buy 80 of these
for the price of the E63.
-80?
-80.
What do you reckon
you could get for it?
I reckon you could
get four grand.
FREDDIE: Four grand?
I'm really into what
we've achieved here, lads,
but if you think
you could get £4,000
for this car,
but if you think
you could get £4,000
for this car,
but if you think
you could get £4,000
for this car,
you've been smoking something.
-Three and a half, then.
-Easy.
PADDY: Although what we
wouldn't be telling
any prospective buyers
PADDY: Although what we
wouldn't be telling
any prospective buyers
is the new 4-litre V8 does make
the thing a bit thirstier.
Now, don't tell me
you don't love
a bit of filler bingo.
Now, don't tell me
you don't love
a bit of filler bingo.
Now, don't tell me
you don't love
a bit of filler bingo.
Full gas on the pump,
furthest away
from the next £10 loses.
Full gas on the pump,
furthest away
from the next £10 loses.
Full gas on the pump,
furthest away
from the next £10 loses.
So, you've just got one lift,
that's it. One lift.
Yeah, one lift.
0-10, 10-20, 20-30.
The loser consumes...
-Oh, God, no.
-You're sick.
-I'm going to leave
that there as a warning.
-FREDDIE AND PADDY: Ugh!
-I'm going to leave
that there as a warning.
-FREDDIE AND PADDY: Ugh!
-I'm going to leave
that there as a warning.
-FREDDIE AND PADDY: Ugh!
There's something wrong
with you, Harris.
PADDY:
Not the Turkish Delight!
FREDDIE:
Three, two, one, go.
Go on, Harris.
It's a fast one, this, Paddy.
-PADDY: This is fast.
-FREDDIE: Isn't it fast?
Seven, eight...
Nine, ten!
-11, 12, 13, 14...
-Oh, he's miles away!
-It's away. Miles away, Paddy!
-He's nowhere near.
9.78.
Right, I'm on.
Here we go. 16...
-I beg to differ
on the stupidity.
-18, 19...
-I beg to differ
on the stupidity.
-18, 19...
-I beg to differ
on the stupidity.
-18, 19...
Nowhere near!
-76!
-I'm going to win!
No, no!
He's having the Turkish!
-FREDDIE: I bottled it.
-PADDY: He's having the Turkish!
How can you get 70s?
CHRIS: 2p behind.
-That's got in my head.
-I've never felt
pressure like this.
-That's got in my head.
-I've never felt
pressure like this.
You need to get within
22p of the next £10. Go!
No feathering, Paddy.
21, 22, 24, 25.
Stop!
49! You put me off!
-You shouted stop and he went...
-He stopped! He stopped!
49.
PADDY: Oh...
Come on, let's see it.
Oh, the old chocolate-covered
toilet block.
FREDDIE: Oh,
I can smell it from here.
(LAUGHTER)
This is not what
I signed up for.
I don't feel good, boys.
I don't feel good.
I do.
PADDY: Back on the road,
we'd been told to head
inland for our next test.
PADDY: Back on the road,
we'd been told to head
inland for our next test.
PADDY: Back on the road,
we'd been told to head
inland for our next test.
I've got the chess board, boys.
That is brilliant.
But because Flintoff
is basically a giant toddler,
almost immediately,
he needed a wee.
And that meant Harris'
next test was, well,
nothing to do with the car.
FREDDIE:
Yeah, it all came out all right.
Beautiful, beautiful.
-Oh, God.
-Beautiful.
Do you mind if I just
wipe my hands?
No! No!
Covered in piss!
-Oh, no, he's not happy.
-He's gone.
PADDY:
He's not happy.
FREDDIE: Get in
the driving seat, Pad.
(PADDY AND FREDDIE CHUCKLING)
PADDY: Once Harris
had towelled off,
we got back on our way.
PADDY: Once Harris
had towelled off,
we got back on our way.
PADDY: Once Harris
had towelled off,
we got back on our way.
-I mean... Oh.
-We're going to be quiet
for a few minutes.
-I mean... Oh.
-We're going to be quiet
for a few minutes.
-I mean... Oh.
-We're going to be quiet
for a few minutes.
I don't want to hear a word
out of either of you.
I'll go on the Etch A Sketch.
(PADDY WHISTLES)
PADDY: Soon, we
were closing in on
our next family car showdown.
PADDY: Soon, we
were closing in on
our next family car showdown.
PADDY: Soon, we
were closing in on
our next family car showdown.
And, worryingly,
this one looked hilly.
PADDY: Oh, hello.
Hey, I've got one of them.
-PADDY: I've got a Discovery.
-You've what?
-I've got a Discovery.
-Are you blind?
What's wrong with a Discovery?
CHRIS: It's
a terrible looking car.
It's the worst
piece of car design
of the last five years.
It's the worst
piece of car design
of the last five years.
It's the best off-road
family car there is.
-How often do you
go off-road in it?
-I'm not disputing that,
-How often do you
go off-road in it?
-I'm not disputing that,
-How often do you
go off-road in it?
-I'm not disputing that,
I'm saying how can
you say that's ugly?
-It's a fantastic looking car.
-That's a great looking car?
-It's really not.
-It's a beautiful car.
Look at the back end.
-You've been
spoiled, Harris.
-You're wrong, Paddy.
-You've been
spoiled, Harris.
-You're wrong, Paddy.
-He is right, he's right.
-Who's this?
Hello.
-What?
Are you sure
you don't need that?
Dogger.
Wind the window up quick.
"No family holiday would be
complete without a night
"in the great outdoors.
"You will now race to your
campsite atop that hill."
CHRIS: Oh, yes,
our rival holiday-makers
were back for
an off-road showdown.
Our campsite was on the
other side of the valley,
across four, gruelling miles
of challenging terrain.
Up against the world's most
capable family off-roader
and armed with nothing
more than a big compass,
the Overtaker
had its work cut out.
And, to make matters worse,
Flintoff was at the wheel.
RADIO: Three, two, one...
-PADDY: Go, go, go!
-FREDDIE: Straight on?
-PADDY: No, to the right.
-CHRIS: To the right!
This is not an off-road vehic.
PADDY:
Go, go! Come on!
CHRIS: Typically, Stig was
taking the direct route.
And we had no hope of
following in the Overtaker.
PADDY: Go easy.
Go easy with the car.
It's a prototype!
PADDY: Go easy.
Go easy with the car.
It's a prototype!
PADDY: Go easy.
Go easy with the car.
It's a prototype!
FREDDIE: Oh!
CHRIS: So, while
the Discovery
was being fired straight
CHRIS: So, while
the Discovery
was being fired straight
at the countryside...
we would need to stick
to the tracks...
If you see a right, take it.
keep up the pace...
Jesus (BLEEP BLEEP)!
CHRIS: ...and stay
out of trouble.
-PADDY: Stay off the edges.
-Trust me and trust the car.
Normally, I'd say use
your common sense,
but you quite clearly
don't have any.
CHRIS: A couple of miles in,
The Stig's route was
getting stickier.
And the Discovery
was slowing down.
To the right! To the right!
With Freddie
still pushing hard,
this race was on.
We'll catch him,
we'll catch him.
Don't get carried away
with your speed.
-All right, Chris,
I've got this.
-Up to the right, here.
To the right.
FREDDIE: Paddy,
are you all right?
Paddy, you all right?
CHRIS: Luckily,
Paddy was all right.
But, more importantly,
the same couldn't be said
for the Overtaker.
I'm not a mechanic,
but in technical terms...
that's (BLEEP)!
PADDY: At the hands
of two stupid, incompetent,
cack-handed idiots,
PADDY: At the hands
of two stupid, incompetent,
cack-handed idiots,
PADDY: At the hands
of two stupid, incompetent,
cack-handed idiots,
our ultimate family car
dream was dead.
1,300 quid...
down the pan.
Or perhaps not.
Because, with the family
car score now 1-1,
there was still one test left.
And, overnight,
those two stupid, incompetent,
cack-handed idiots
had been busy.
Look, we promised
him we'd fix it. We have.
And now he gets to drive it.
We can't do more
than that, can we?
And now he gets to drive it.
We can't do more
than that, can we?
And now he gets to drive it.
We can't do more
than that, can we?
It's not how he imagined
it, though, is it? Look at it.
-The rule is you bend it,
you mend it.
-Ooh...
-The rule is you bend it,
you mend it.
-Ooh...
FREDDY: You all right, Pad?
PADDY: It's not
the prettiest, is it?
It's a miracle
it's still working.
What exactly
have you done to it?
CHRIS: Well, we've taken
all the windows out.
-Yeah, I've seen that.
-This still works, look.
PADDY:
That will come in handy.
Too soon. Too soon.
We've got it going,
that's pretty much it,
Paddy, to be honest.
We've got it going,
that's pretty much it,
Paddy, to be honest.
We've got it going,
that's pretty much it,
Paddy, to be honest.
Well, go on, then, jump out.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
What's happened to the doors?
This is the Dukes Of Hazzard
model. I'm Bo, he's Luke.
No, you come
out the side, Freddie.
What family car
do you have to get
in and out of the windscreen?
What family car
do you have to get
in and out of the windscreen?
What family car
do you have to get
in and out of the windscreen?
CHRIS: Don't walk on it, Fred!
I mean, there's a little
part of me is impressed
that you've managed
to get the roof back on.
FREDDIE: How
little is that part?
Very little.
-You all right?
-MAN: Hello.
"The most important aspect
of any family car is safety."
Are you listening?
"To test how safe your ultimate
family car really is,
"you will now compete in
Britain's crashiest motorsport,
"banger racing."
Hold that.
You're not driving this
and you're not driving this.
Leave it to me.
Out the way.
How do I get in again?
-FREDDIE: Can I help you?
-Not sure how that's helping.
Go on, go on. Get your head in.
CHRIS: You've basically put me
in the position I were in
the last time I were in the car!
Jesus Christ!
PADDY: So, with the Overtaker
somehow back from the dead,
it was now heading straight in
to the most unforgiving test
of them all.
And to help keep it
out of the grave it had
just been dug up from,
And to help keep it
out of the grave it had
just been dug up from,
And to help keep it
out of the grave it had
just been dug up from,
I'd been given two stupid,
incompetent, cack-handed
idiots as outriders.
FREDDIE: Harris,
where do you want me?
I think I want you
left rear gunner. I'll go right.
Check.
PADDY: But there was one
more added challenge,
heading up the competition
was the safest family car
of them all,
an old Volvo estate.
And at the wheel of
this Swedish tank...
Hello, my patty-pattycake.
Oh, God, it's the German.
I thought they got rid of her.
Hi, Sabine. Good to see you.
I came all the way from
Germany to meet you.
Bang!
FREDDIE: The rules
of the derby were simple,
the winner would
be the last man,
or woman, left standing.
And Harris and I would
do whatever was necessary
to keep the Overtaker
on track,
proving it truly belonged
among the family car elite.
They cannot scratch
the Overtaker!
FREDDIE: I'd take a bullet
for you, Paddy. We've
got you, son.
FREDDIE: I'd take a bullet
for you, Paddy. We've
got you, son.
FREDDIE: I'd take a bullet
for you, Paddy. We've
got you, son.
PADDY: Do not let them through.
No-one's coming through here.
You couldn't be in safer hands.
I feel like Kevin Costner
in The Bodyguard.
-PADDY: Keep it up!
-You're my wicket, Paddy.
PADDY: A few laps in,
and the outriders
were holding firm.
PADDY: A few laps in,
and the outriders
were holding firm.
PADDY: A few laps in,
and the outriders
were holding firm.
Paddy, I'm on your (BLEEP).
PADDY: But, as the heat
of battle intensified,
our defences began to weaken.
Oh, it's getting messy.
Watch him, Harris!
Take him out, sunshine!
I'm getting a right battering.
PADDY: Where's my outriders?
Paddy! I'm coming for you!
Agh!
PADDY: That must
have been Sabine.
PADDY: Freddie, face
the right way, for God's sake!
The carnage continued.
And, then, disaster struck.
(ENGINE SPLUTTERS)
I think she's dead.
FREDDIE: Harris,
get back and help.
Harris!
CHRIS: Knackered.
Harris is out.
PADDY: Down to just
one defender
and with him facing
his own fight for survival,
things were looking bleak.
Whoa, whoa,
Sabine's having a go at me.
(SABINE LAUGHS MANICALLY)
Oh, it's slippy. It is slippy.
Holy...
Watch the paintwork, son!
PADDY: And before long...
FREDDIE: I've just skidded...
Blooming heck,
I'm using the wall.
PADDY: Where's Flintoff?
FREDDIE: Come on, baby.
Oh, no!
Oh, who was that?
It was Paddy.
Can you not see I'm stopped?
PADDY: Flintoff was
out of the running
with only himself to blame,
and the Overtaker and
I were now on our own.
I can sense impending doom.
SABINE: Paddy!
Sweetheart!
I'm coming for you.
PADDY: I'm on me own!
And we're surviving.
SABINE: Whoo!
Bye-bye!
(SABINE LAUGHS MANICALLY)
Yes, it's heating up.
Yes, she's been bashed about,
but she's still
got a beauty to her.
Yes, she's been bashed about,
but she's still
got a beauty to her.
Yes, she's been bashed about,
but she's still
got a beauty to her.
This remarkable machine
had done us proud.
She'd given everything,
but, in the end,
the fight was
to prove too much.
Yes!
Eat my dust!
PADDY: It doesn't feel good.
Oh, God! Oh, no!
Oh!
Bye, Paddy.
PADDY: Oh, Overtaker...
We've had a good innings.
You were the ultimate
family car to me.
(PADDY SIGHS)
Oh, my God.
SABINE: Ha-ha! Number one!
(AUDIENCE APPLAUSE)
Love that car.
Now, joking aside
just for a second,
there was a moment then
-when I flipped the car...
-Yes.
I was so concerned.
I was shouting to Paddy.
I couldn't hear anything in the
back. I thought I'd killed him.
So, I think, Chris, you should
apologise for being so reckless.
-Thank you.
-What?
I was coaching you.
You was egging me on. You were
saying, "Go faster, go faster!"
-You're capable of independent
thought, mate.
-No, I'm not.
-You're capable of independent
thought, mate.
-No, I'm not.
-Run at that camera.
Run into it.
-This one?
-Run at that camera.
Run into it.
-This one?
No, don't.
You are a moron, aren't you?
Look, despite you
two clowns' best
efforts to wreck this car,
Look, despite you
two clowns' best
efforts to wreck this car,
Look, despite you
two clowns' best
efforts to wreck this car,
you've got to admit, it came
through with flying colours.
It's the ultimate family car.
Come on, boys.
I think you've got to let it .
-I think it's time to bury
the hearse.
-Oh, no.
-I think it's time to bury
the hearse.
-Oh, no.
Mate, it's as dead as the people
who go in the back.
No, no, no, it's not!
No, it's not! Hey, hey.
-Hang on, hang on.
-What's he doing?
Let's see if she'll start.
Here we go.
Oh, it's still damp in here.
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, God!
-(ENGINE STARTS)
-(AUDIENCE CHEERS)
She's alive! She's alive!
That's all for tonight.
Thank you so much for watching.
-See you next week.
-I can't believe it!
Ta-ra!
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(ANGELIC MUSIC)